<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: crime | DigiRidge]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.chris.digiridge.co.uk/blog/categories/crime/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.chris.digiridge.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-07T12:10:04+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.chris.digiridge.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Ridgers]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fare well laptop.  I'll miss you.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.chris.digiridge.co.uk/blog/2014/04/03/fare-well-laptop-ill-miss-you/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-03T20:58:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.chris.digiridge.co.uk/blog/2014/04/03/fare-well-laptop-ill-miss-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two weeks ago today I had my laptop stolen while visiting my girlfriend in Liverpool.  Which is great.  Since then I&rsquo;ve been doing all the regular stuff you do when your stuff gets nicked as well carrying on with my degree stuff, but it hasn&rsquo;t been a fun process to go through; particularly regarding police involvement.  I feel bad even typing this, but at this point I may as well put it out there and let anyone that reads this make up their own minds about whether or not the response has been reasonable.  So here it is&hellip;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Firstly, I&rsquo;d like to just go through how I would have handled the situation given the events and what resources <strong>I believe</strong> that the UK (more specifically Merseyside) police service have to hand.  I can&rsquo;t guarantee that every assumption I make here is correct, but I can assure you that I&rsquo;ve put a fairly large amount of thought into the subject over the last two weeks.</p>

<p>I was sitting in the McDonald&rsquo;s restaurant next to my girlfriend at a breakfast bar style booth facing out of the restaurant through a glass window.  The area of the restaurant was a small narrow section near the toilets, and to my left I had a wall divide which my bag was resting next to; placed but not wedged next to my foot.</p>

<p>At a none de script point throughout our meal, I noticed an individual appearing to be eyeing up my bag via the reflection in the window, and I checked to ensure that it was still there, which it was.  5-10 minutes later however, it was not.</p>

<p>I immediately proceeded to the front of the restaurant and scanned the multitude of persons looking for my rucksack but it wasn&rsquo;t there.  I then pulled aside one of the front of house employees and requested that they check their CCTV while I called the police, which they agreed to do.</p>

<p>I then rang the police via 101 (none-emergency contact number) and explained the situation.  From here <strong>this</strong> is what I would have done:</p>

<p>I would first confirm the time of the theft.  Given the immediate nature of the report, it was extremely likely the thief was yet to leave the area.  Even with a very generous elapsed time of 20 minutes, and a brisk walking pace of 6.5km/h, there was a very limited area in which the thief could have possibly been.  For a more visual representation of this area: see the below map lovingly entitled &ldquo;Places my stuff could have possibly been while I was on the phone with the police feeling sick.&rdquo;</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/theftmap.png" title="Places my stuff could have possibly been while I was on the phone with the police feeling sick" ></p>

<p>While initially it looks like quite a large area, 6.5km/h is a very brisk walking pace and in addition McDonald&rsquo;s then confirmed which direction he had headed in.  Which potentially halves the area.  Finally this distance doesn&rsquo;t take into account navigating roads and footpaths: it&rsquo;s very unlikely they would reach the far extremities of the perimeter.</p>

<p>This is where my assumptions start entering the realm of hearsay.  This is the big brother state: I can&rsquo;t believe for a second there aren&rsquo;t dozens of CCTV cameras within that area, or that the police and/ or governing body wouldn&rsquo;t be aware of them or lack the authority to access them in order to fight crime.  I would pull up a live feed of all the cameras in the area and their footage since the laptop was stolen, following the thief&rsquo;s progress faster than real time in order to pin point his current location: I&rsquo;d then send a local patrol to arrest the little shit.</p>

<p>&hellip; My feelings on the subject are pretty intense I&rsquo;ll admit.</p>

<p>This to me seems to be a reasonable sequence of events, given the nature of the police and reputation the UK has in regards to CCTV.  Taking it even further: lets assume that the thief gets to Lime Street Station and boards a train before the police arrive.  There&rsquo;s only so many places that train is going to stop.  It&rsquo;s not difficult to decide that a likely course of action would be to wait for him to get off at a station and follow his progress from there before a local patrol picks him up.</p>

<p>But, for the sake of argument, I&rsquo;ll state that this isn&rsquo;t possible:  the CCTV is broken, it doesn&rsquo;t exist, he&rsquo;s just not on it.  Vampire or such nonsense. He&rsquo;s still in that circle somewhere with my stuff and it&rsquo;s the best chance the police will ever have at finding him.  In addition: it&rsquo;s 23:15.  The streets aren&rsquo;t exactly packed, least not up near Lime Street Station/ Brownlow Hill way.  The sooner the police get there, the more likely the situation is to be resolved.  Send someone.  Anyone.</p>

<p>But, again, let&rsquo;s assume there is no one available.  There&rsquo;s a large fight broken out on the other side of town and all the police are there containing drunk rioters or something.  The thief makes it out of the circle and steals away into the night.  He WAS on CCTV at McDonald&rsquo;s.  And he was, as it happens, eating a meal prior to the incident: HOW DID HE PAY FOR IT.  It is 23:15 at night.  Every pawn shop in Liverpool is currently closed, meaning that he has to hang on to my goods for at the very least the next 9 hours.  As soon as an officer becomes available, he is sent to the 24/7 (and thus open) McDonald&rsquo;s to view and retrieve a copy of the footage, along with to check if the thief payed for his meal via card transaction: credit or debit I don&rsquo;t care, they both have an address registered to them.</p>

<p>The police then go to that address and arrest the guy.  Or at the very least check that the cards weren&rsquo;t stolen in addition to my laptop.  If it&rsquo;s there, then the laptop is successfully retrieved and the world sleeps happy.</p>

<p>But alas to no avail, said thief was smart enough to have paid by cash before stealing peoples equipment.  What next?  Well, according to the tales of the McDonald&rsquo;s employees, events like this are an unfortunately frequent occurrence on the premises.  They have already recounted two stories to me about individuals having their possessions stolen.  So there must be a suspect list right?  People regularly stealing from a restaurant covered in CCTV must lead to regular police involvement and suspects. The guys been caught on camera eating there, does he match any of the persons previously suspected of stealing stuff?  Has he been arrested before?  Well we&rsquo;ve got the CCTV and now we can check.</p>

<p>This is where my rant ends.  I can say what I would have done or would have liked to have done from now until the world grinds to a halt in a &lsquo;Walking Dead&rsquo; esque apocalypse.  It&rsquo;s not what happened.  But again: I don&rsquo;t want to slag the police off.  I want them to be doing the best job they can given the circumstances, and without detailed knowledge of the available resources, I can&rsquo;t say that they&rsquo;re not.</p>

<p>This however <strong>is</strong> what happened, all personal feelings removed.  You can decide for yourself whether or not the police response would be to your satisfaction.  After all, if you&rsquo;re in the UK, it&rsquo;s your service.  It should be serving you to your satisfaction.</p>

<blockquote><p>22:15(20/03/14):  I arrive in Liverpool.</p>

<p>22:46: I notice my laptop is missing.</p>

<p>23:14: I finish the initial report with the police. I&rsquo;m told that the call is deemed as a level 2, and that the typical response time is up to 60 minutes.</p>

<p>00:00(ish): I receive a phone call from Merseyside police service informing me that the patrol dispatched to attend has been diverted to an emergency call out, as a result they will be delayed.</p>

<p>>00:00:  A patrol car pulls up outside, two uniformed officers exit.  I approach them stating, &ldquo;&hellip;I&rsquo;m guessing you are here to see me, here about the laptop?&rdquo;.  They respond stating that they&rsquo;re sorry, but they are not.  They are off duty and work on the other side of town.  They then enter the restaurant and proceed to order food.  They later leave while I continue to wait for the dispatched patrol to arrive.</p>

<p>00:45(ish): I receive a second phone call from Merseyside police service informing me that there are no officers available to attend.  I am asked for a place of contact.  I give my girlfriends university accommodation address as a place of contact.  When asked how late would be unacceptable for officers to contact me I state that no matter how late it is, I will be awake as I will be waiting for them, and therefore to arrive as soon as possible.  I am told that they will arrive at some point later in the night.</p>

<p>07:20: I receive a phone call apologising that nobody has made it out to me yet, and I am told that someone will attend as soon as possible.</p>

<p>11:40: I ring 101 and am connected to the CMU (Crime Management Unit).  I receive an apology that no one has attended, and an apology that I was informed that any response was en route.  According to the individual; due to the fact that the incident was captured on CCTV, and my testimony can not be used beyond that, there is no reason that they would respond in person, or that I should be informed as such.  The police service will collect the footage in their own time and contact me at a later date.</p>

<p>Mid afternoon: I make a second phone call to 101 (and the CMU).  I enquire as to whether the CCTV has been picked up from the restaurant.  I am told that it has not, and that the typical response time is 72 hours, and will involve the incident being logged as crime(?) report.  I am told I will be contacted within 72 hours and that if not I should get in contact.  (NOTE: 72 hours from the initial report is 23:00(+&ndash; 15 min) on the 23/03/14; a Sunday night.)</p>

<p>24/03/14:  I ring 101 and am connected to Merseyside Police Service, and then the CMU.  I am informed that on the previous day, the incident was logged as crime report, and given a log number 10 digits long and different from the initial record number originally given to the incident. I am told that I will be contacted later regarding collecting my statement (after collecting the CCTV).</p>

<p>03/04/14(two weeks after the initial incident):  I contact 101, am connected to Merseyside Police Service, and while attempting to connect me with the individual responsible for handling my case, I am told that the constable in question is on a rest day; he will be emailed and will contact me the following day between 08:00-16:00.  The person I am speaking with is unable to update me on the incident/case, including whether or not the CCTV has been retrieved from the restaurant in question.</p></blockquote>

<p>And that is as neutral and current an account in regards to police contact as I can manage.  I could point out all the stages that I have felt anger at the police regarding the response (particularly the morning after the incident occurred once the shops had opened), but it would do nothing but obscure the account of what happened.  Not that it should matter, but I did inform the police of the value of the stolen goods which was >£1500 pounds.  Obviously monetary loss is relative to the wealth of the individual that lost it, but still.  I&rsquo;m simply recounting the facts so that you can decide for yourself how adequate the response has been.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll make a separate post that describes everything I&rsquo;ve been doing since then that doesn&rsquo;t involve the police.  After a two week &lsquo;cool down&rsquo; period however, I&rsquo;ve come to the conclusion that I&rsquo;m level headed enough to post a reasonable online statement; after all the thief has had more than enough of an oppurtunity to sell my stuff, and as a result if it hasn&rsquo;t turned up already I&rsquo;ll almost definitely never see it again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
