<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[DigiRidge]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.chris.digiridge.co.uk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.chris.digiridge.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-01T04:47:52+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.chris.digiridge.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Ridgers]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's in Bits]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.chris.digiridge.co.uk/blog/2014/03/03/its-in-bits/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-03T01:40:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.chris.digiridge.co.uk/blog/2014/03/03/its-in-bits</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I write this I&rsquo;m flicking between 6 different things:
this website, learning Octopress, learning ruby, university project A,
university project B and Season 1 of Game of Thrones.  It is 01:46 in the
morning and I have a Doctors appointment at 09:00: this is my life&hellip;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>&hellip; and it&rsquo;s in bits.</p>

<p>This site is (hopefully) going to turn into a fair representation of who I am,
offering potential employers/ anyone a deeper look into my life then can be
fairly represented on a C.V.  Part of this however means juggling several
very different things at once; this site represents the face of my first foray
into Cloud PaaS&#8217; as well as my first time publicly promoting my work which until
now I&rsquo;ve always been contented to keeping to myself.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve linked my Github account which documents a fair chunk of the things I do, and
as this site pulls together, I&rsquo;ll include some of the other pieces of work I&rsquo;ve enjoyed
completing; it&rsquo;s quite an eclectic mix, not least because since my college days my
general attitude has been &lsquo;do everything.&rsquo;  As much as the idea of specialising into an
area of computing sounds attractive, I can&rsquo;t help but feel a sense of unease at the
thought that by doing so I&rsquo;ll limit my ability to complete a fully polished piece of work.</p>

<p>Such is the point of teams though is it not?  I have my own thoughts on this that I&rsquo;ll
almost definitely talk about in a later post, but for now, this will suffice for a first post.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s something that I can look and smile at.  A starting point for what I hope to be a very
satisfying project.</p>

<p>Projects&hellip;. Game of Thrones&hellip;.. Bed&hellip;..</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
